London, UK 💡

Sales Consultant

## – Professional Profile —

I believe the key to success in my career has been a solid understanding of both people and processes, and the way they interact. A restaurant is probably one of the best environments to learn operations, as the ever-present customers provide instant feedback; it's obvious what works and what doesn't, and you must constantly manage multiple priorities.

I've worked in several such businesses and spent the last 6 years managing them with overall P&L responsibility. This encompasses functions and processes such as: facilities management, recruitment, training, customer experience, marketing and finance. The most important lesson I've learned in these senior roles is not just mastering these things, but training staff to understand them in such a way that they operate well without my constant presence. This has, of course, been crucial in my work as a multisite manager.

Decided of leaving hospitality, I am now looking for a role in which I can gain experiences in to the world of sales and customer service.

# - SELECTED SKILLS AND EXPERTISE -

- Hospitality Management
- Operations
- Multi-Site Management
- People Management
- Customer Service
- Facilities Management
- P&L Responsibility
- Recruitment
- People Development

## - Career Summary -

## independent Consultant, London | myPOS

Sept 2022 – Present

Starting a new field with myPOS. I have passed their own Academy, gained the certificate of Expert level and Consultant. I am now targeting our main clientele groups via a mixture of strategies; phone calls, internet, social media, in person.

#### Multisite Manager, Covent Garden and Canary Wharf | The Alchemist,

Apr 2022 – Sept 2022

Having successfully covered my manager during her maternity leave, I was handed overall responsibility for our two flagship sites, where I led an improvement across all commercial metrics, overhauled and improved operations and built two excellent teams. The Alchemist is a chain of restaurants established in Manchester, and I played a key role in building our presence in London.

- I lead two teams with a total headcount of 120 across two sites.
- Increased revenue by 25% to £75–100k per week. I held full P&L responsibility for both locations.
- Improved operations by working closely with an Assistant General Manager, training her, supporting her, and encouraging continuous excellence.
- Responsibilities: P&L, reporting, facilities management, training, Designated Premises Supervisor, recruitment, HR processes & customer experience.

This invigorating challenge saw me opening a new location for the Alchemist in the legendary Covent Garden. I took a central role in recruitment, helping to organise an open day, as well as drawing on my own connections in the city, to build a top-performing team. I also covered my manager's maternity leave for 6 months, managing 6 sites in London and elsewhere.

- Managed 6 sites for a 6 month period.
- Held full P&L responsibility and led the bar to £80k per week in sales.
- Used a variety of channels to recruit excellent staff that the customers love.
- Led 60 team members including Head Chef, Bartenders, Assistant General Managers, Sous Chefs etc, Restaurant Manager & Duty managers.
- Responsibilities: P&L, reporting, facilities management, training, Designated Premises Supervisor, recruitment, HR processes & customer experience.

## General Manager | Be at One Cocktail Bars, Piccadilly Circus, London Apr 2016 – Apr 2018

In charge of the Piccadilly Circus operation, I led a team of 14. This is a particularly challenging location in the portfolio as it only has a 150px capacity and is always full.

- Led the 14 strong Bar Team, as well as all other ancillary staff.
- Finished the financial year 2017-18 £63k ahead of sales target and £87k ahead in net profit, with 3.98% growth over the previous year.
- Achieved the bar's £64k per week record sales result.
- We won Best Bar in 2017, an internal competition covering all 19 venues.
- Responsibilities: Stock, all ordering, invoices, cash handling, facilities management, training, customer experience, recruitment, rotas, sales, marketing and everything else required to make a busy business unit more successful.

## Assistant General Manager | Be at One Cocktail Bars, Soho, London

Sep 2015 – Apr 2016

This was a formative role in my career and prepared me well for taking on complete P&L responsibility for a busy, service-based operation.

- We achieved 30% growth in the financial year 2015-16.
- Won Best Venue out of all bars in the group.
- Trained the next Assistant General Manager who went on to get her own site.

# ——— EARLIER ROLES ————

Duty Manager   Be at One Cocktail Bars, Bank & Spitalfields, London	Sep 2014 – Sep 2015
In-Store Trainer   Be at One Cocktail Bars, Bank, London	Mar 2014 – Sep 2014
Bartender   Be at One Cocktail Bars, Bank, London	Jun 2013 - Mar 2014
Bartender   Marriott Hotels, Marble Arch, London	Mar 2013 – Jun 2013
Head Waitress   Buddha-Bar Hotel, Budapest Klotild Palace, Budapest	Apr 2012 – Feb 2013
Bartender   Hotel S'Agres, Menorca	Jun 2011 - Oct 2011
<b>Executive Lounge Attendant</b>   Marriott Hotels, Budapest	Jun 2009 – May 2011

## - Education & Professional Development-